Software Engineer

ALBERTO VALLEJO

ABOUT

Hi reader, I'm Alberto (or just Beto as my friends call me) and a Software Engineer. I'm located in a small city near the pacific coast called Colima. Here I've found a warm place surrounded by nature and a lot of friendly people, but also I got the chance to build a career as a Web Developer.

Back in **2012**, I started working in a web consultancy where I first started to build web applications using Ruby on Rails and had the chance to be part of an experienced team that was building websites of all sizes, sure that helped me a lot to start with the right foot in this path.

Today, I'm still working as a Full Stack Developer; I've had the pleasure to work with startups from Mexico, the US, and Canada, being part of outstanding teams, and I like to think that I've contributed to reaching all the companies goals. But coding is not everything in my life. When I'm far from the computer, I like to watch a soccer or rugby game or be on the road riding my motorcycle along with beautiful landscapes.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science.

2006 - 2010. Universidad de Colima.

Colima, México

+ Awarded with "Premio Peña Colorada" to the 1st. place in Bachelors in Computer Science generation 2006 - 2010 of the Universidad de Colima.

EXPERIENCE WORKING WITH:

Amazon AWS, Heroku

Ruby on Rails Javascript, React, Redux, TypeScript, JQuery Git, Github, BitBucket Asana, Jira, Trello SQL, MySQL, PostGreSQL Unit Test, Integration Tests

CONTACT



github.com/alberto-vallejo-ci



javr1088@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/albertovallejo/

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Native

English

Good written skills

Advanced Communication Skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer @ HiMama (Toronto, ON, Canada)

Nov 2021 - Present https://www.himama.com

Currently, I'm a Full-Stack developer of HiMama's engineering team. My primary responsibility here is to contribute to the Backend side, delivering clean and efficient code for new features, reactors, redesign, bug fixing, and adding Tests to grant coverage to any new code.

Other responsibilities are participating in sprint planning, pointing tickets, contributing to Code Reviews, and expressing ideas to find solutions to issues that the team could face.

Software Development Engineer @ RoverPass (Austin, TX, USA)

April 2019 - Nov 2021 (+2 years)

www.roverpass.com

As a Full-Stack developer in the Roverpass engineering team. My responsibilities were more focused on the Back-End work with Ruby on Rails, activities like developing efficient queries from a PostgreSQL database, building services (like payment services using Stripe), growing the test coverage, and developing the site API using GraphQL are part of my daily activities.

Nonetheless, I also have some time the chance to work in the site's Front-End developing or improving features built with React. Other important duties that are part of my responsibilities, are: Participating in the sprint planning to define the course of action for new features or refactors, helping to set the effort on tickets, doing Code Review to Pull Requests and helping less experienced teammates.

Software Development Engineer @ Everest (Austin, TX, USA)

Aug 2017 - Nov 2018 (+1 years)

www.everfest.com

I joined the growing Everest engineering team as a Full Stack developer. It was a great opportunity but with great responsibility because it was the first that they accepted a remote member for the team, so I knew that communication was the key to success.

As a Full Stack Dev, one of my primary responsibilities here was to help to improve the site's performance by applying best practices mainly in the DB queries and Rails models and start to build the site's suit test using Unit Test, Rspec, Capybara.

On the Front-End side, I had the opportunity to start working with React and Redux to switch the conventional Rails views to use these tools around all the user interfaces, improving the existing pages and adding new ones.

Software Development Engineer @ Devgile (Colima, COL, México)

May 2014 - Aug 2017 (+3 years)

www.devgile.com

I was part of DevGile's engineering team; in that time, I had the opportunity to work with around six different projects, each one with unique challenges. As a Full-Stack Developer, I worked on both sides of those projects since helping to design new data structures for the databases to change the sites' User Interface completely.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer @ Crowd Interactive (Colima, COL, México) Apr 2012 - May 2014 (+2 years)

Working at Crowd Interactive helped me to set the basis of my development career. As a Jr Back-End Developer, I started using the "Pair Programming" strategy with more experienced teammates. Still, I quickly started getting assigned bugs or futures to do on my own. Increasing or Improving the Tests coverage was also an assignation added with every task I developed.